Thanksgiving is a national holiday in the United States.
It celebrates the time when the pilgrims came from Europe
and gave thanks to the Native Americans
for helping them gather food and have a great meal
after their long trip.
Thanksgiving in my family is really wonderful.
We get together.
Everyone in the family comes to my house,
including my cousins and my aunts and uncles.
And we have a very, very, very large meal
in the middle of the day at around 5 p.m.
And it's the only meal of the day.
It's really nice because everyone comes together early
in the day and starts cooking together.
The main part of the Thanksgiving meal is the turkey.
And it's a lot of fun creating all of the things
that accompany the turkey, including the stuffing, which
usually is made of rice and spices.
And then there's the cranberry sauce,
which is very popular for Thanksgiving meals.
And there is, of course, a lot of corn
because corn is something that is
native to the United States.