So I grew up in a suburban town in the US and there is a type of house in
suburbia that we refer to as a McMansion. Now McMansions are really big
houses that try to look like multi-million dollar mansions without
the cost of millions of dollars having gone into build the actual house. I always
thought of McMansions they're ugly they look kind of tacky they're not really my
vibe. McMansions are usually mass produced houses so they all look similar
to each other and because they're built with quantity in mind over quality they
have a lot of characteristics that I don't really think makes sense and I
don't know anything about architecture or building houses. Personally McMansions
aren't really my style they lack the personality I think that regular mansions
have and because they're built in neighborhoods with other houses like
very close by they also lack the privacy that regular mansions would have
with big big yards and lots of land to kind of like maintain privacy and so
that lack of privacy I think also makes the house not feel as luxurious as a
regular mansion would.