I live in Queens in New York City in a townhouse and it is a three-story house with a basement.
The basement is kind of its own little apartment.
There's a bed and a kitchen and a bathroom and we have our laundry down there and that's
basically where we keep most of our old things that we don't want to throw away.
And then on the first floor we have our regular kitchen and our dining room and our living
room.
So there are three rooms that are separated by walls but not by doors, they're separated
by a curtain.
And then on the second floor are all the kids' bedrooms and the library.
So we have my bedroom and my sisters, two of my sisters share a bedroom and we have
our own bathroom which has a shower in it and a sink and a bathtub and a toilet.
And then we also have the library on the second floor where we just have everybody's books
and a nice cozy reading area.
And then on the third floor there are also three rooms.
There's another kitchen on the third floor, it's much smaller because it used to be another
apartment as well.
And it's my stepfather's office and then my parents' bedroom and then my little brother
has a small bedroom next to my parents' bedroom.