Are women and men equal in the workplace?
I don't think they are, but I probably don't think that it will ever be possible either
because a man and a woman aren't necessarily interested in the same things as men.
They have different interests, like in jobs.
For example, if you look at the degrees people do at uni,
you have some subjects that have the majority will be men and others the majority will be women.
No one's forced them to do that subject, that's just what they're interested in.
I also think that maybe women will always have different priorities.
There is always the fact that women, they want children,
they are the ones who have to give birth and have to take time off work.
Unfortunately, I don't think that women can be equal to men because of that huge fact.
Also, there's another fact that when women don't have kids and they are ruthless in the workplace,
they're then said that they're then compared to a man, which I find quite unfair.
A lot of women feel that they have to act that way, to be promoted and to do very well for themselves.
I do still think there is discrimination to some extent as well.
Also, women are paid less, so that's another discrimination.